Harold L. Graham Papers PC.5104
Harold L. Graham Papers
1933-1937 and undated
PC.5104
33MSS-104
0.200
The Works Progress Administration, later renamed the Work Projects Administration (WPA), was the largest of President Franklin Roosevelt's New Deal agencies. It employed millions to carry out various public works projects, such as building and road construction. The first WPA workers were from the Transient Bureau and came to North Carolina's Outer Banks in 1934. Among other projects, they planted stabilizing grasses to create dunes along the ocean front and aided in the construction of the Waterside Theatre, where The Lost Colony drama is performed each summer. One of the chief projects of the WPA was the construction of dunes for over 100 miles of North Carolina's barrier islands. Lt. Harold L. Graham was an army finance officer stationed at WPA Camp Wirth located on the north end of Roanoke Island, North Carolina. This collection includes correspondence, receipts, financial records, and army training course books related to Graham's WPA service.
Graham, Harold L.
Outer Banks History Center
Box Box 1
Collection Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series: Correspondence, Financial Records, U.S. Army Records, and Photographs.
Access Restrictions
Available for research.
Historical Note
The Works Progress Administration, later renamed the Work Projects Administration (WPA), was the largest of President Franklin Roosevelt's New Deal agencies. Created under the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act, it was meant to bring financial relief to the millions unemployed during the Great Depression. The WPA carried out various public works projects, such as the construction of buildings, bridges, and highways. The first WPA workers were from the Transient Bureau and came to North Carolina's Outer Banks in 1934. Among other projects, they planted stabilizing grasses to create dunes along the ocean front and aided in the construction of the Waterside Theatre, where The Lost Colony drama is performed each summer. However, one of the WPA's biggest jobs was the construction of a duneline for over 100 miles of North Carolina's Barrier Islands. Lt. Harold L. Graham was an army finance officer stationed at WPA Camp Wirth located on the north end of Roanoke Island, North Carolina.
Custodial History
Formerly classified as 33MSS-104.
Acquisitions Information
Donated by Robert Midgette in 2008.
Collection Overview
This collection includes correspondence, receipts, financial records, photographs, and army training course books related to the WPA service of Harold P. Graham.
United States. Army; United States--Works Progress Administration
Manteo (N.C.)--History--20th century
- Correspondence, undated; 48054; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:2.1)
- Financial Records, 1936-1937 and undated; 46884; Graham, Harold L.
  - Receipts: L. D. Tarkington General Merchandise, undated; 41794; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:3.1)
  - Canceled Checks, 1936-1937; 41795; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:3.2)
  - Bank Statements, Bank of Manteo, 1936-1937; 41796; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:3.3)
  - Payroll Record, January 1937; 41797; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:3.4)
- U. S. Army Records, 1933-1937 and undated; 46885; Graham, Harold L.
  - U. S. Army Inactive Duty Training Schedule, 1936-1937; 41798; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:4.1)
  - Army Regulations No. 35-3420, Finance Department, undated; 41799; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:4.2)
  - Army Extension Courses, 1933-1934; 11132; Graham, Harold L.
    - Signal Communications For All Arms and Services, 1934; 41800; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:4.3)
    - Defense Against Chemical Warfare, 1933; 41801; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:4.4)
- Photographs, undated; 48055; Graham, Harold L. (Folder 1:5.1)